Support Admin Watch on
kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
I heard the lawyer that
would represent
Don Mariano in court...
Was appointed by
General Seleno himself.
I sense that they will
deliberately lose his case.
- Sonya? Sonya!
- Wait...
Are you alright?
My wife is pregnant.
I was on my way
to the festivities, Ignacio
when Helena
stopped me.
Now I think
she did it on purpose.
Don Mariano is
hereby sentenced...
To death.
And don't be worried.
I am ready
to face my fate.
Remember,
there are battles we lose.
But when you fall,
that doesn't mean
you won't get back up
again and continue fighting.
I promise.
I will never
leave your side.
You are summoned
by Judge Valenciano
at the town hall.
He revealed that
you were the one who schemed
The fake news
about Don Mariano
being involved with the rebels.
Your presence is expected.
We ask Don Alejandro to
remove his clothes as well...
and to prove the statements
made by Captain Corpuz.
That it was in fact, Don Alejandro,
who convinced them...
To mark themselves with an X...
As a sign of their settlement.
It is true that Mr. Pipoy
is with the rebels.
When I learned that...
I asked help from General Sergio.
But...
He raped...
and abused me.
Sergio, defend yourself.
Yes, I admit it.
I raped and abused Cristeta.
Captain Pedro Corpuz
and General Sergio Alfonso...
are sentenced by this court...
To death.
All of them are angry at Don Alejandro.
And maybe, that's how
Juanito feels about me too.
Miss, it's been days since
you last ate something.
Do you want me to bring you food in here?
I am not hungry.
Teresita...
The letters I've sent to Juanito...
Did he answer any of them?
Even just one?
Miss,
I'm really sorry, but...
Mr. Juanito hasn't replied
to any of your letters.
Even after General Sergio
and Captain Corpuz were executed last week,
The civil guards are still
closely watching the Alfonso family.
No one has been out of their hacienda.
They didn't even see Sergio's body.
Even Mr. Ignacio,
He wasn't allowed to see his father's body.
They are bound to leave San Alfonso today.
They'll be exiled to a far away place.
No one knows where except the judges.
I need to see Juanito...
Just once...
for the last time.
Miss...
Even just once.
Let the children go to the pier.
They just want to bid
farewell to their friends.
No one will leave this house.
Anyone who disobeys me
will suffer great consequences.
Please consider your children.
I don't need to consider anyone.
Miss, would you like me
to deliver your message
to Mr. Juanito instead?
No. I must do it. But...
How do we leave when Father's here?
You're always acting like this.
Don't you feel pity for your children?
Get out of here.
Leave me be.
If I'm not mistaken,
before, didn't you leave
the house through the...
Window!
Even in the last seconds,
I hoped he will turn and see me.
But he didn't.
He didn't even look at me.
I won't ever see Juanito again.
I didn't even get to say how I truly feel.
Under the orders of the Governor-General,
who represents the empire of Spain...
From this day forward,
14th of October, 1891.
The new officer-in-charge
of San Alfonso would be..
Governor Vicente Flores.
I would still continue
the plans and projects of the Alfonsos.
After all, they served our
town for quite a long time.
In line with this,
I appoint General Seleno Salvacion
as head of the peace corps
and leader of the civil guards.
Even though the General couldn't be here...
Due to an important meeting in Manila...
Instead let us give a warm welcome
to our new judge.
Judge Maximo Rosalejos.
What's happening?
I feel like this is all wrong.
And as the newly-appointed governor...
I'd like to give recognition
to someone who has
provided jobs and livelihoods.
And has been the reason behind
the booming economy of our town.
My fellow citizens,
let us give him a round of applause.
The one who shall be my right-hand man.
The second most powerful
official in San Alfonso.
Don Alejandro Montecarlos.
Thank you, my friend.
Thank you, thank you.
Is it possible that they both conspired
to bring down the
Alfonso family?
And another thing,
There's nothing written in the diary
about Don Alejandro becoming an official
Did destiny really change?
I need to talk to Mother Olivia.
But...
She went somewhere nobody knows where.
Carmelita.
Maria.
Sleep evades me.
How about you?
I have a lot on my mind.
So much happened one after another.
Changes.
And people we have lost.
I don't know what to feel.
I can sense you are worried for Juanito.
But you should probably accept
that maybe you're not
meant for one another.
How would you know if
someone is not meant for you?
There are many...
Obstacles that can stop two
people from loving each other.
Aside from the strength
and resilience of their
affection for one another.
Relationships must also depend on destiny.
Yes...
Juanito loves you.
And that is also how you feel.
But you're separated from each other now.
You don't even know where he is.
Their family are considered criminals.
And in no circumstance...
Will Father ever agree
to let you marry Juanito.
Carmelita.
What you feel for Juanito...
will just bring pain
and conflict.
How about you and Eduardo?
Do you think you're meant for each other?
I knew right from the start,
that Eduardo and I aren't
going to end up with each other.
Father will never agree
to let me marry someone...
Ordinary.
But I also know that you're aware...
The heart doesn't
really listen to the mind.
I still followed what my heart wants.
But now...
I finally realized that
we're not for each other.
Beautiful, isn't it?
Oh no, there's a dead body!
- Good Lord!
- Who could that be?
- They found it in the river.
- Who was it? It was found in the river.
- Go ahead.
- Yes, General.
That poor soul. Who could it be?
Good day to you, Miss Carmelita.
What happened? Why is there a dead body?
The body was found on the riverbank.
General Seleno isn't here right now
that's why I was the one
who received the report.
When did you get promoted to General?
My rank was promoted
when I went to Cavite with General Sergio.
Before he got arrested and...
Taken back here to San Alfonso.
General Leandro! Cristeta's still alive!
It was Cristeta who was found in the river?
Miss, I should go.
Take her to the hospital!
Quickly!
She needs to survive.
She's the only one who can prove that
Don Mariano, Sergio Alfonso,
and Captain Corpuz weren't rebels.
In doing so, absolving
Juanito's name as well.
I lied.
It wasn't true that...
Mr. Sergio ever abused me.
We have feelings for each other.
And something already happened between us.
But...
When I heard that...
He was already arranged...
To get married to someone else.
That's why...
I testified against him.
Mr. Maximo promised me a new home,
somewhere far away.
And he also bribed...
Mr. Pipoy
to testify
against Don Mariano.
But...
he murdered
Mr. Pipoy after.
I can feel...
...that I'll be next.
That's why...
I did the act myself.
I finally tricked those bastards.
Cristeta...
Cristeta?
Help!
Cristeta!
Cristeta?
Help!
Cristeta!
Cristeta?
Help!
Cristeta...?
- Carmelita! Let's talk at home.
- Cristeta?!
Come on!
- I'm so sorry, Father!
- Alejandro!
- Alejandro! Please stop!
- Father!
Stop this, please!
Father, don't! Please!
Alejandro! That's enough...
You always go against my word, Carmelita!
What were you doing at the hospital?!
And why were you talking to the girl
who testified against the Alfonsos?!
Father...
Why did the mark disappear from your back?
Are you saying...
That I had a hand in their
deaths and imprisonment?!
Why did you stay quiet?
When Don Mariano was sentenced, why?
Carmelita...
Captain Corpuz said that...
You reconciled with them,
and that you all had the mark
in your back at the same time.
As a symbol of your friendship.
Carmelita!
Stop right now! Do not accuse your father!
And now...
You're believing Corpuz's
lies more than me?!
That's enough, Alejandro...
There's only one telling the truth, Father.
And I have proven now, that you...
You're lying.
Father, no! Please don't!
Please have mercy! Stop, Father!
Enough!
Stop hurting your children!
General Leandro came here earlier.
He wants to talk to Carmelita.
What did you say?
I asked him to leave.
I told him this isn't the right time.
But maybe it is time.
If they truly love each other,
why should we stop them?
Alejandro!
I don't know what's happening
to our daughter, but I think..
Marriage with straighten her life out.
I miss him already.
Maybe if he was here,
everything will be easier for me.
Everything feels better
whenever I see his smile.
For me, that's the most
beautiful poem I have ever read.
Carmelita, my dear.
Please understand your father.
You know he has a very short temper
and he has a heart condition.
I hope you could understand
that he's human too.
He got hurt with your accusations.
Mr. Leandro visited earlier, by the way.
I mean, General Leandro.
I asked him to return another day.
I know you're still not feeling well.
Dear,
I hope you understand.
Your Father and I only wish
for the best interests
of you and your sisters,
I hope you can open your mind
and see that we only wish for your safety.
Your Father and I agreed to
push through with your wedding.
My wedding to Juanito will push through?!
So that you may know the
responsibilities of a mother and a parent.
And that your days may be filled with it.
I knew you'll be glad to hear that news.
Now I'm sure that you do love him.
Very well, you rest early.
Tomorrow, General Leandro
and Governor Flores will be back.
What?
I am to be engaged to Leandro?
Carmelita, dear? Wait!
Father.
I do not want to get married.
Please take back your word.
And why are you unwilling?
Didn't you scheme with Juanito
just so you could stop your wedding?
You also helped him get
closer to Helena Flores...
And you told every single one of us
that it is Leandro you love.
It's true that I didn't want
the wedding to happen
for the sake of Juanito.
But I don't have any feelings for Leandro.
Answer me.
Why are you opposing this engagement?
- Because...
- Carmelita, dear.
Please don't take this any further.
I really don’t know what
else to do with you, Carmelita.
Can't you see?
I did this
because I'm trying to look out for you.
Because I want you to be happy.
Even though you are filled
with hatred and doubt for me.
I still did it because that
is what good fathers do.
Because I want to be a good father to you.
But it seems your heart is already set.
Where is my youngest daughter?
Where is my sweet Carmelita?
Who was full of affection?
Loving and always obedient to me?!
Why?
Why does it seem like...
I don’t know the person
I’m looking at anymore?
Why?
I apologize, Father.
I'm still not ready yet.
I don't want to get married.
I know that there's
nothing written in the diary.
And Carmelita and Leandro
aren't meant to be married.
Miss.
Where are you going?
Are you headed somewhere?
You're leaving me too?
What?
I wouldn't leave you even if I could, Miss.
Don't worry, it's not
just me who's leaving.
You'll be leaving as well!
So go ahead and dress
up, so that's we won't be late
to the ship heading to Sugbu.
What are you saying?
Didn't Miss Maria and
Miss Josefina tell you?
Oh, and by the way,
your parents left early with your sisters.
They're attending the
feast of Governor Flores.
You were not woken up because
today is also our departure
with Mother Olivia to Sugbu.
Our departure?
Towards Sugbu?
That's right.
Last night, Mother Olivia
talked to Don Alejandro.
She said you needed more time to think.
Especially after everything
that has happened and,
that you were deeply saddened
when the Alfonsos were exiled.
A family that has become close to you.
That's why Don Alejandro
agreed
to let you stay in Sugbu for two weeks.
Before finally setting up a date
for your wedding to General Leandro.
Why are you happy about it?
Mother Olivia requested that I join you
so that you won't get too lonely, Miss.
I will have our belongings loaded first.
Mother Olivia.
Where have you been?
Why didn't you tell me
where you'll be going?
My dear...
I settled an important thing.
What's important now...
Is that I was able to take you away
from Don Alejandro even just for a while.
We have to do something
to stop your wedding to Leandro Flores
What should we do?
I suspect that...
Destiny has already changed its course.
I don't know what's gonna happen next.
But...
There's one thing I know for sure.
Make sure Juanito lives.
That is your mission.
The day of his death has changed,
and that is what I fear the most.
Mother Ofelia, good day to you.
Good day to you as well.
This is Carmelita and Theresita.
It's a pleasure meeting
you, Miss Carmelita.
And welcome to you as well, little miss.
This is Mother Esperanza.
Mother.
Dear...
You are also here to learn.
Don't worry.
We won't charge you.
Just take care of Carmelita,
with all your heart, that will be enough.
Thank you very much.
I will take our belongings
from the carriage.
Thank you.
- Mother Esperanza, please help her.
- Of course.
Well, I'll call the other nuns to help you.
We'll be waiting for them.
You seem to be in good spirits.
Maybe.
I might just really need some
time and space to not be stressed.
Sometimes, dear...
The more we take someone out of our mind...
The more we can't forget them.
The best way to solve that is...
Not fighting what you feel.
But Juanito and I can't
end up together, right?
You weren't supposed
to fall in love with Juanito.
But just like I've said...
Destiny has changed its course.
So, does that mean Juanito and I could...?
Your mission...
Is to save Juanito from dying.
So that you can return to your own time.
What do you think pushes a person
to continue living?
Love?
If you think about it...
Love is the reason why...
The Lord Jesus Christ chose to die...
In order to save us from our sins.
Because He so loved us deeply.
That is also the same for people
who is suffering immensely.
Why do you think...
They fight to live?
And hold on to hope?
It's because of all the people
who care and love them truly.
Even though...
humans are always making mistakes.
The Lord always forgives us.
Because the Lord loves us.
Now...
I truly understand.
Why Juanito fell in love with you.
Not because you're
pretending to be Carmelita.
But because you...
You...
Are Carmela.
He fell for the real you.
Just like twins with identical faces...
They still have differences.
In appearance, you may be Carmelita.
But when it comes to the heart...
And the mind...
You are Carmela.
Now...
Do you still doubt Juanito's feelings?
- Miss Carmelita,
- Mm?
there's something I need to tell you.
What is it?
I'm not sure, but...
I think I saw Mr. Juanito at
the fish area in the market.
Did he see you?
I don't think so.
I wanted to call him but
I was with Mother Ofelia at the time.
Maybe it wasn't him.
How unlikely it is for us
to see Mr. Juanito here.
Teresita, listen to me.
That was really Juanito.
I saw him yesterday.
I'm sorry I didn't tell you.
I wanted to keep it a
secret that he lives here.
We have to be careful.
If Father and Mother learn
that he was exiled here...
They'll force us back to San Alfonso.
What should we do?
Miss, why don't we just
approach Mr. Juanito?
I'm not ready to face him.
Who are you?
And where are you from?
We are not bad people.
A Tagalog from a wealthy family.
Who are you?
Why are you here?
Are you spies?
Father Caloy!
They're daughters of the
family we serve in Bulacan.
Please excuse them, Father Caloy.
These ladies are our guests.
Alright then.
Don't let them roam around alone.
They might get into trouble.
I wanted to ask,
General Leandro.
Are you and my daughter
really in love with each other?
In love or not,
we all know you need
this engagement more than us.
To clean the
reputation of your daughter.
Juanito!
Can we just talk for a bit?
I don't want to have
anything to do with you.
Every time I see you,
I remember the betrayal
your father did to our family.
Just pretend we didn't meet.
Juanito!
It's Mother!
No wedding shall happen
between Carmelita and Leandro.
I am here to inform all of you...
That Carmelita decided
to be a servant of the church.
- Father!
- Alejandro!
I hope you promise
that the mouse
will never leave his beloved cat.
Carmelita,
I hope you will
choose me in the end.